神烦警探  第三季第二十三集
翻译  A.I.
翻译  waterdancing
翻译  RT1
翻译  好吧蛋蛋
校对  好吧蛋蛋
后期  柒一四
深影字幕组出品
凯瑟琳・海格尔主演的爱情喜剧片
实习医生格蕾里的韩裔演员
三十秒前
饶舌歌手
有报道说里诺是全美最抑郁的城市
2000年代后期的经济衰退对该地区经济造成了巨大冲击
Tone Loc演唱的歌曲
一周后
珊瑚棕榈公寓 佛罗里达州
一个月后
Blue Skies - Ella Fitzgerald
秋季回归 谢谢观赏
快啊 快啊 警监 快接电话啊
Come on, come on, Captain, pick up.
你的朋友鲍勃在秘密地
Your friend Bob is secretly
帮"屠夫"吉米・菲吉斯做事
working for Jimmy "The Butcher" Figgis.
这通电话不容错过
This is a call you're gonna want to take.
鲍勃肯定对他下手了
Bob must've done something to him.
或者他们在谈论些超级无聊的东西
Or maybe they're talking about something super boring,
比如土豆或豆子
like potatoes or beans.
白米 糙米...
White rice, brown rice...
以上是我喜欢的米类中的一部分
those are just some of the rices I love.
还有印度香米
Also basmati.
这回都说全了
Uh, that's all of them now.
我早该看出惠伦探员被收买了
I should've known Agent Whealon was dirty.
以前有迹象的
There were signs.
他穿过一次V领衫
He wore a V-neck once.
鲍勃
Bob.
你居然无动于衷
You did nothing?
这是我最后悔的事
It's my greatest regret.
至少他还活着
Well, at least he's still alive.
等他醒过来 咱们就撬开他的嘴
When he comes out of the coma, we'll get him to talk.
你可否去找些吃的来
Would you mind getting us some food?
我不想吃佩拉尔塔买的这些巧克力棒
I can't fathom eating these candies that Peralta bought us.
巧克力是魔鬼的角豆[巧克力的低脂替代品]
Chocolate is the devil's carob.
而撒旦把角豆当葡萄干吃
And carob is Satan's raisin.
我去楼下餐厅看看
I'll go down to the cafeteria,
或许能找到些没烤过的面包片
see if I can scare up some untoasted bread.
美味
Yum.
噢 雷蒙德
Oh, Raymond.
我把钱包忘在了...
I forgot my wallet in my...
鲍勃 你杀了他
Bob, you've killed him.
现在我也不得不杀了你
And now I'm going to have to kill you.
我从来没有如此震惊过
I've never been more shocked.
糟糕 太糟糕了
This is bad. This is really bad.
鲍勃会带霍尔特去哪里呢
Where would Bob have taken Holt?
不知道 图书馆吗
I don't know, the library?
或者索引卡的工厂
Or an index card factory?
有没有会计博物馆这种东西
Is there such a thing as an accounting museum?
等下 我找到了
Hold on. I got this.
我知道警监的"寻找手机"功能的密码
I know the captain's "find my phone" password.
他在医院
He's at the hospital.
他还在医院 你是个天才
He's still at the hospital. You're a genius!
我真想接受表扬 但事实是
Well, I'd love to take credit, but the truth is,
人生并没那么难
life just isn't that hard.
咱们得去医院
We got to get to the hospital,
而且要快
and we got to get there fast.
- 那应该让我开车 - 为什么
- Then I should drive. - Why you?
我生无可恋 开车的时候也一样
I have nothing to live for, and I drive like it.
好的 就这么办
Okay, let's do it.
杰克来电话了
Jake called.
我们必须立刻返回纽约
We need to get back to New York right now.
不 不
No, no, no, no, no.
你不能就这么走了
You can't just leave.
我们将来可能还能用到这些人
We may need some of those contacts in the future.
你要跟她们告别 而且要走心
You're gonna go say good-bye, and you're gonna mean it.
虽然我为最高法院撤销了
So while I'm happy the Supreme Court
对我的判决而感到高兴
threw out my conviction,
但离开你们真的让我非常伤心
I'm also really sad to be leaving all of you.
贝萨妮 我知道你是个纵火犯
Bethany, I know you're an arsonist,
但现在是时候点燃整个烹饪界了
but now it's time to set the culinary world on fire.
茜拉(误) 你有天使般的嗓音
Sheila, you have the voice of an angel.
不管谁成为你的下一任音乐制作人
Whoever your next music producer is,
别捅死他就好
maybe don't stab him.
珍 你是个纳粹主义者 咱俩没啥共同语言
Jen, you're a Nazi. We never really clicked.
别再犯罪了 女士们
Stay innocent, ladies.
不 不 怎么回事
No, no, no. What happened?
他二十分钟前停止了心跳
He flatlined 20 minutes ago.
这屋子里那两个男的 他们去哪了
The two men who were in this room, where did they go?
我不知道
I don't know.
好吧 谢谢了
Okay, thanks.
吉娜说霍尔特还在楼里
Gina said Holt is still in the building.
但具体是哪里呢
But where?
我要进入他们的思想
I have to get into their heads.
"鲍勃 你在干什么"
"Bob, what are you doing?"
"我在犯罪 雷蒙德"
"I'm breaking the law, Raymond,
"因为我是最坏的人
"Because I'm the worst.
现在装作没事一样走出这间屋子"
Now walk out of this room as if nothing is happening."
"你不会得逞的 鲍勃
"You'll never get away with this, Bob.
杰克正在赶来
Jake is on his way.
他是个了不起的警察 他会救我的"
He's a great cop, and he's going to save me."
"真的吗 他似乎很不成熟"
"Really? He seemed so immature."
"对 他看起来是那样
"Yes, he seems that way,
但我了解真正的杰克
But I know the real Jake.
他就像我的儿子
He's like a son to me.
等这一切都结束了
And when this is all through,
我们会一起去自驾游"
we're going on a road trip together."
- 杰克 - 罗莎 嘘
- Jake. - Rosa, shh!
我在破案呢
I'm working on the case right now.
这有点不对劲
That's weird.
标志牌的H上有个污点
There's a smudge on this sign right over the H.
这个H也有污点
There's a smudge on this H too.
天哪 为什么你会摸医院的东西
Oh, my God, why would you touch a hospital thing
然后还放到嘴里
and then put it in your mouth?
是巧克力
It's chocolate.
出色的直觉 一定要相信自己
Great instincts. Never doubt yourself.
霍尔特在试图用我给他的
Holt is trying to send us a message
巧克力棒给咱们传递信息
using the candy bar I gave him.
自然点 雷蒙德
Just act natural, Raymond.
吃巧克力棒
Eat your candy bar.
我吃不下 太恶心了
I can't. It's disgusting.
我不管
I don't care.
H代表霍尔特
H is for Holt.
他在引导我们过去找他
He's leading us right to him.
我们现在只需要
Now all we have to do
跟随巧克力的踪迹
is follow the trail of chocolate.
这...
This...
我当警察就是为了这一天啊
this is why I became a cop.
查尔斯 怎么这么半天
Charles, what took so long?
我还想在起飞前把这身行头换下来呢
I want to get out of this suit before we take off.
我们哪都去不成了
We're not going anywhere.
航班订满了
The flight is booked,
而且排队的人还有很多
and there's already a huge stand-by line.
什么 我们必须得赶上这趟航班
What? We have to get on that plane.
你刚才态度够坚定吗
Were you stern?
艾米 你知道我不坚定的
Amy, you know I wasn't.
我能解决
I've got this.
霍尔特有危险 而那位女士碍了我的事
Holt's in danger, and that lady's in my way.
永远不要挡在老师的宠儿和她的老师之间
Never get between a teacher's pet and her teacher.
好了 马甲女士
Okay, vest lady.
我不管你需要做什么...
I don't care what you have to do...
亲爱的 你怀孕了
Oh, you sweet thing, you're pregnant.
我怀孕了
So pregnant.
真是个奇迹啊 对吧
What a miracle, right?
请给我些特别待遇吧
Please give me special treatment.
我把她一顿虐 猜猜虐出了什么
I ripped her a new one, and guess what fell out.
两张去纽约的机票
Two tickets to New York.
升级到头等舱的
First class upgrade.
整个停车场
No chocolate smudges
没有一个巧克力渍
in this entire parking garage.
一楼到五楼也没有
Or on floors one through five.
我们彻底跟丢了
We're officially lost the trail.
除非...
Unless...
不对 这不是巧克力
No, that's not chocolate.
- 这是什么啊 - 什么
- What is that? - What?
别再吃一次了
Don't eat it again!
等等 收到条信息
Wait, getting a text.
- 是霍尔特警监 - 他在哪里
- It's Captain Holt. - Where is he?
他说什么
What'd he say?
"五下里地"
"Inib rue tiid."
等等 我又收到一条
Wait, I'm getting another one.
"卡噶了" 这都看不懂啊
"Ink obrvs whiz." These are nonsense.
他嘴被堵住了
He's been gagged.
堵嘴怎么会影响发信息呢 斯库利
How would that come through in a text, Scully?
等下 我知道怎么回事了
Wait a minute. I know what's going on.
他是偷偷在口袋里发的信息
He's secretly trying to text us from his pocket.
我死后 请代我向凯文问好
When I die, please give Kevin my regards.
要我跟他说什么
What shall I tell him?
"向你问好"
"Regards."
斯库利 这些像是你天天发的那种奇怪信息
Scully, these look like the weird texts you always send.
触屏手机无法对我的手指做出正确反映
Touch screen phones don't respond correctly to my fingers.
因为我被电击过太多次了
It's because I've been electrocuted so many times.
等等 我们肯定可以逆推出来
Hold on, I bet we can reverse engineer this thing.
斯库利 把这个输到你手机上
Scully, type this into your phone.
"五下里地" 两个I
"Inib rue tiid." Two "I"S.
出来的是 "窝在老定"
It came out, "Imm on rha rooj."
"我在楼顶" 他在楼顶
"I'm on the roof." He's on the roof!
上帝保佑你 斯库利 也保佑你那奇怪的坏死的手
Oh, God bless you, Scully, and your weird, dead hands.
你和希区柯克太犀利了
You and Hitchcock are killing it!
- 我的天啊 - 赶紧走吧
- Oh, my God. - Let's just go.
不许动 放下武器
Freeze! Drop your weapon!
再靠近一步 我就杀了你们警监
One more step, and I kill your captain.
好了 鲍勃 你们在这干什么
Come on, Bob. What are you doing up here?
为什么来楼顶
Why are you on the roof?
天啊
Oh, my God.
你准备像美式忍者那样
You're gonna zip-line off of this thing
靠滑索下去
like an American ninja.
真是个酷炫的脱身计划
That is such a cool escape plan.
实际上 我是想把雷蒙德推下去
Actually, I was gonna throw Raymond over the side
伪装成观鸟时发生的意外
and make it look like a bird-watching accident.
得了吧 你真以为会有人...
Oh, please, do you think anyone's gonna actually...
天才
It's genius.
一个街区外有一只红尾鹰
There's a red-tailed hawk roost a block away,
而我像傻子一样 兜里揣着一副
and I've got a pair of micro binoculars in my pocket,
袖珍望远镜
like a fool.
好的 我承认我错了
Okay, well, I stand corrected.
放下枪投降吧
Just drop the gun and surrender.
如果你指证菲吉斯
If you turn on Figgis,
最后结果未必会太糟
this doesn't have to end badly for you.
你还留着那份包含所有对他不利证据的档案吗
You still have that file with all the evidence against him?
你是说你交给我的那份
You mean the one you handed me?
当时那是个好主意 我们都这么以为
That was a good idea at the time; we all thought that...
还留着 那份档案在一个安全地点
Yes, that file's in a safe place,
你们永远别想找到
and you're never getting it.
别傻了 鲍勃 你寡不敌众
Don't be foolish, Bob. You're outnumbered.
寡不敌众个臀部
Outnumbered, my bottom.
菲吉斯的人已经在路上了
Figgis's men are on the way.
是的 我叫了援兵
Yes, I called for backup.
警监 趴下
Captain, down!
泰瑞把你放倒了
Oh-ho, Terry took you down!
时机刚好 警长
Nice timing, Sarge.
你怎么知道我们在这
How'd you know we were up here?
警监把所有的H都用巧克力标出来了
Captain marked the Hs in chocolate,
我一下就联想到了我们现在所站的地方
which I instantly connected to the giant helipad H
直升机降落点上的H
we're on right now.
真酷
Oh. Cool.
真酷 我们也破解出来了
Cool, yes, we also solved that.
直接跑来了楼顶
Came straight up here to the roof.
一秒钟都没瞎逛
We didn't wander around even for a second.
我们都聪明着呢
We're all smart.
聪明 这是个很好的藏身处
Smart. This is a good hiding space.
斯库利 你怎么躺下了
Scully, why are you lying down?
因为有床啊
'Cause there was a bed here.
你还把鞋脱了
You took your shoes off.
好吧 一队可疑的黑色SUV
All right, look, a bunch of sketchy, black SUVs
刚停在了外面
just pulled up outside.
不是菲吉斯的人 就是碧昂斯磕到了脚趾
Either it's Figgis's guys, or Beyoncé stubbed her toe.
不要开这种玩笑 杰克
Don't even joke about that, Jake.
否则我们的首要任务就要改一下了
That would be our new number one priority.
我们得请求增援
We have to call for backup.
菲吉斯在纽约警署和联邦调查局里都有人
Figgis has people in the NYPD and the FBI.
祝你们好运
So good luck with that.
背叛联邦调查局固然不对
Wow, betraying the FBI is one thing,
但你居然会嘲讽 鲍勃
but sarcasm, Bob?
好吧 只能靠咱们自己了
All right, we're on our own.
我们得把鲍勃从医院带走
We got to get Bob out of this hospital
转移到一个安全的地方
and to a secure location,
一个纽约警局不知道的地方
someplace the NYPD doesn't know about.
警监 你是成年人了 借我们用下你的湖边小屋
Captain, you're a grown-up; let's just use your lake house.
最后说一次 不是每个成年人都有湖边小屋
For the last time, not all grown-ups have lake houses.
可以去我的公寓
We can go to my apartment.
没人知道我住在哪
No one knows where I live.
我以为你请艾米去过一次
I thought you had Amy over there once.
没错 玩得很愉快 我第二天就搬走了
Yeah, it was fun. I moved the next day.
就去罗莎家了
Rosa's place it is.
他们知道鲍勃的长相
Well, they know what Bob looks like,
但他们从没见过我们
but they've never seen us.
他们只知道我们是一大帮警察
They think we're just a big group of cops.
如果我们看起来不像警察呢
What if we didn't look like cops?
# 我来自纽约 我来自纽约 #
# I'm from New York, I'm from New York #
# 我来自来自纽约 #
# I'm from, I'm from New York #
# 我来自纽约 耶 #
# I'm from New York Yeah #
# 我来自 #
# I'm from #
很好 大家的扮相都不错
Great, everyone looks fantastic,
我们的帽子看起来也很正常
and our hats look normal.
警长 你真是穿手术服的衣架子
Wow, Sarge, you are just stuffed into those scrubs.
你是怎么做到的
How do you do it?
锻炼和控制饮食 没什么难的
Exercise and diet. It's not that hard.
对我来说似乎挺难
Eh, seems pretty hard to me.
我觉得我做不到
I don't think I'm gonna do that.
这勾起了我的回忆
This brings back memories.
我孩童时喜欢玩扮医生的游戏
I loved playing doctor as a child.
癌症已经扩散了
The cancer has spread.
准备后事吧
Get your house in order.
我们可以这样溜出去
So we can sneak out like this,
但是鲍勃怎么办
but what about Bob?
不用担心 我已经处理好了
Not to worry. I've got that covered.
希区柯克
Hitchcock.
没错 他被绑着 嘴也堵上了
And, yes, he is bound and gagged under there,
不过更重要的是 你刚才说"鲍勃怎么办"
but more importantly, you said, "What about Bob?"
那是一部电影的名字[天才也疯狂]
That's the name of a movie.
霍尔特引用了流行文化元素
Holt made a pop culture reference.
好了 走吧
All right, let's go.
好 我们再把下机策略
Okay, let's go over our exit strategy
过一遍
one more time.
2A座的乘客会需要有人帮她取包
Seat 2A is gonna need help with her bags.
她的胳膊细得跟小树枝似的
She has twig arms.
要是她挡了我们的道 我就使出怀孕这招来
So if she blocks us, I play the pregnancy card.
记住 扔下行李然后...
And remember, leave our luggage and...
指望在失物招领处能找回来
Roll the dice with lost and found.
我知道 我已经对着你画在呕吐袋上的这张地图
I know; I've been studying this map you drew on the barf bag
研究了四十分钟
for 40 minutes.
对不起 只有工作
Sorry, working is the only thing
能让我停止担心同事
keeping me from worrying about the squad
和焦虑不已
and completely spiraling.
需要热毛巾吗
Hot towels?
说了无数次了 不用
For the billionth time, no!
我们不需要你那煮过的烂布头
We don't want your boiled rags!
不了 谢谢
No, thank you.
似乎你的焦虑并没怎么缓解
I don't know if it's keeping you from spiraling.
我们干嘛不暂时放空一下呢
Look, why don't we just take our mind off everything?
我们在头等舱 可以免费看电影
We're in first class. We get free movies.
什么 不要
What? No.
队员们有危险
We can't enjoy ourselves
我们不能在此时享受
while the squad is in danger.
那不公平
That's not fair.
艾米 我们要在这困三个小时
Amy, we're trapped here for three hours.
别的事也做不了
There's nothing else we can do.
好吧 那就看一部吧
Fine, I'll watch a movie,
但是不许看我们会喜欢的
but nothing we'll like too much.
- 也不许看新上映的 - 当然
- No new releases. - Of course not.
我们就看列表里的第一部好了
We'll just put on whatever's first alphabetically.
《27套礼服》
"27 Dresses."
病人脑梗了
His cerebral blood circulation is infarcted.
给我拿根脑室内导管来 快
Get me an ICP catheter, stat!
厉害呀 警长
Wow, that was amazing, Sarge.
我经常看《实习医生格蕾》
I watch a lot of "Grey's Anatomy."
那个电视剧出奇地真实
That show's surprisingly accurate.
是哦 我看过的那集
Yeah, the one episode I watched,
病人屁股里有颗炸弹
there was a bomb in the guy's butt.
那集好看
Oh, that's a good one.
他快不行了
He's crashing!
注射十毫升糖皮质激素
Push 10 ccs of corticosteroids,
还要准备急诊室做手术减压
plus prep an ER for surgical decompression!
我都不知道自己说的是什么
Look, I don't know what any of this means,
但我觉得自己就像吴珊卓
but I feel like Sandra Oh.
医生 需要我准备手术台吗
Doctor, do you need me to start a line?
不用了
Oh, we're good.
你说他快不行了 给你注射器
You said he's crashing. Here's a syringe.
好嘛 我会用这个刺穿他的皮肤
Oh, good, I'll use this to puncture his skin.
有人来了
Uh-oh, we got company.
这人屁股里有个炸弹
Uh, this man has a bomb in his butt!
我们得走了
We got to go.
银色警报 银色警报
Code silver, code silver.
分头走
Split up.
你没事吧
You okay?
没事 没事
Yeah, yeah.
我只是看得太投入了
I'm just so into the movie,
真担心凯瑟琳・海格尔
you know, really worried about Katherine Heigl
和她的制衣事业
and her dressmaking business.
不好意思 制衣事业
I'm sorry, dressmaking business?
她的建筑师事务所吗
Her architecture firm?
她的蛋糕店
Her cupcake bakery.
她主编的杂志
The magazine she edits?
珍是一个热爱户外运动的企业家的
Jane is the executive assistant
行政助理
to an outdoor lifestyle entrepreneur.
你都没在看的
You're not even watching!
对不起 我没法集中注意力
I'm sorry. I can't focus.
我还在焦虑
I'm spiraling.
我就知道
Ugh, I knew it.
要是连《27套礼服》都不能分散你的注意力
If "27 Dresses" doesn't distract you,
那就彻底没辙了 真的
nothing will, nothing will.
那现在怎么办
So what do we do?
我们就拥抱这焦虑吧
We're gonna embrace the spiral.
我们来谈谈这些恐惧
We're gonna talk about these fears.
马上就要来真格的了
Things are about to get real.
- 麻烦你 女士 - 什么事
- Excuse me, ma'am. - Yes?
我们需要一盒纸巾
We're gonna need a box of tissues
和舒适的毯子
and some cozy blankets.
- 好的 - 还有一样
- Okay. - Oh, one more thing.
- 什么 - 你们有圣代吗
- Mm-hmm? - Y'all got sundaes?
漂亮 便盆砸脸
Nice. Bedpan to the face.
这是便盆吗
That's what this is?
我手都放进去了
Ugh, I put my hands in it.
到处都是菲吉斯的人
Figgis' men are everywhere,
现在医院各个出口
and now there's hospital security
也都布满了保安
at all the exits.
- 我们怎么出去啊 - 别紧张
- How are we gonna escape? - Relax.
有一百万种办法可以偷偷溜出医院
There's a million ways to get out of a hospital unnoticed.
说一个
Name one.
- 打扮成婴儿 - 什么
- Dress up like babies. - What?
你逼我的
Well, you put me on the spot.
你自己提出来的
Well, you brought it up.
好吧 等等 等等
All right, wait, wait, wait.
我真想到了个办法
I've got a real plan.
走右边 走右边
Go right! Go right!
杰克 杰克 杰克 杰克
Jake, Jake, Jake, Jake!
扔下病床 把病床扔了
Abandon gurney! Abandon gurney!
该死
Damn it!
不是鲍勃
It's not Bob.
银色警报 不能让你们出去
Code silver. Can't let you out.
听着 你得帮帮我 我是个FBI探员
Look, you have to help me. I'm an FBI agent.
我是小威廉姆斯
I am Serena Williams.
抱歉 他们都有
I'm sorry. They both suffer from
严重的妄想症
grandiose delusional disorder.
简称GDD
GDD.
我被抓起来做人质了
I've been taken hostage here.
我本来应该在温布尔登的
And I'm supposed to be at Wimbledon.
到我发球了
It's my serve!
不不不 我没发疯
No, no, no, I am not crazy.
他疯了 还疯得很厉害
Yes, he is, deeply.
我们要把他们转到一所戒备森严的精神病院
We need to transfer them both to a secure psychiatric facility.
这位小威廉姆斯刚咬掉了一个医生的鼻子
Serena here just bit off a doctor's nose.
美味得很
It tasted delicious.
行 你们走吧
Yeah, you can go.
不不 通知联邦调查局
No, no, call the FBI.
不 通知大威廉姆斯 通知大威
No, call Venus! Call Venus!
坐下 鲍勃
Have a seat, Bob.
哇 罗莎
Wow, Rosa.
这是你住的地方
This is how you live?
你以为呢
What were you expecting?
不知道 石头墙
I don't know, rock walls,
武器遍地 用水瀑当门
weapons everywhere, a waterfall for a door...
我好像说的是蝙蝠侠的秘密洞穴
I guess I was just picturing the Batcave.
你要一个装满柠檬的花瓶做什么
Why do you need a vase full of lemons?
房间需要一点亮色
The room needed a pop of color.
你到底是谁
Who are you?
行了 鲍勃
All right, Bob,
现在该告诉我们档案放哪了
it's time to tell us where that file is.
我干嘛要说
And why would I do that?
因为我们是你脱身的唯一机会
Because we are your only chance of getting out of this.
你有大量关于菲吉斯的证据
You have tons of evidence on Figgis,
也就是说他很可能会追杀你
which means he's probably gonna kill you.
如果你指证他 我们可以将你纳入证人保护计划
If you turn on him, we can get you into witness protection.
你会在佛罗里达某处得到一间不错的小屋子
You'll get a nice, little house somewhere in Florida.
我想你会喜欢佛罗里达的 鲍勃
I think you'd love Florida, Bob.
其实我没去过 不过皮普保罗的音乐录影带
I've never actually been there, but Pitbull's videos
让那里看起来十分性感
make it seem muy caliente.
我了解菲吉斯 你们比我危险多了
I know Figgis, and you're in far more danger than I.
他会来找你们的
He's coming for you.
而且我保证他的手下一定能找到这里
And I guarantee his soldiers find this place.
不可能
Not gonna happen.
我通过一间空壳公司租下来的
I rent it out under a shell corporation.
是啊
Yeah.
我的邮件都寄到皇后区的一个邮政信箱
My mail goes to a P.O. Box in Queens.
就是
Yeah.
我的邻居都以为我叫艾米莉・戈德芬奇
My neighbors think my name is Emily Goldfinch.
棒棒哒
Oh, yeah.
我的同事都以为我叫罗莎・迪亚兹
People I work with all think my name is Rosa Diaz.
- 对... 等下 什么 - 别操心这个了
- Yeah... wait, what? - Don't worry about it.
- 好吧 - 够了
- Okay. - Enough.
我会让这个混球开口的
I'm gonna get this punk to talk.
鲍勃
Oh, Bob,
有你好看的了
you are S'ed in the B.
我不能失去霍尔特
I can't lose Holt.
我压根还没得到
I've barely scratched the surface
他对我足够的肯定
of the amount of approval I need from him.
我可以吃你的樱桃吗
Can I have your cherry?
来吧 妹子
Oh, get in there, girl.
还有杰克... 我已经好几个星期没见着他了
And Jake... I haven't seen him in weeks,
真难熬
and it's been so hard.
我非常爱他
I love him so much.
天哪
Oh, my God.
我以前跟他说过"我爱你"
I've said "I love you" to him before,
但还从来没加过"非常"二字
but I've never added "So much."
要是我再也没机会说"非常"怎么办
What if I never get to say "So much"?
那我呢
What about me?
要是杰克有个三长两短
What if something happens to Jake,
他就见不到我的孩子了
and he never gets to meet my baby?
我可不想养个
I don't want to hang out with some stupid baby
从没见过杰克的傻孩子
who's never met Jake.
麻烦你 再来两个圣代
Excuse me. Two more sundaes.
我们已经开始降落了
Oh, we've already begun our descent,
所以已经停止供应食物了
so we've suspended our food services.
不好意思 我们尚在经济舱
Oh, I'm sorry. Are we still in coach?
还是在可以为所欲为的头等舱
Or are we in first class where the rules don't apply?
查尔斯 没事
Charles, it's okay.
咱们快着陆了
We're about to land.
你已经让我不再焦虑了
You got me through the spiral.
天哪 你说得对 我们做到了
Oh, my God, you're right. We did it.
很抱歉我们对你大声了
I am so sorry we yelled at you.
但我们还是要打包带走圣代
But we will take those sundaes to go.
我不管你们有没有盖子
And I don't care if you don't have a lid.
想办法搞个盖子
Y'all make a lid.
好了 开始了
All right, here we go.
警监要开始对他下狠招了
Captain's about to lay into him.
你得告诉我档案在哪里
You need to tell me where the file is.
抱歉 雷 我选择不说
I'm sorry, Ray. I'd rather not.
好吧 不是我要的那种彪悍的开场
Okay, not the dynamic start I wanted,
但我确定他只是在热身
but I'm sure he's just getting warmed up.
我可不想再问你一次
I'd prefer not to ask you again.
你听起来好绝望
You sound desperate.
我激怒你了[钻到了你的皮肤下面]
I'm under your skin.
在我皮肤下面的只有
The only things under my skin
皮脂腺 毛囊
are oil glands, hair bulbs,
神经纤维 血管
nerve fibers, blood vessels,
和一丁点脂肪组织
and a bit of fatty tissue.
你忘了还有鲁菲尼小体
You forgot about Ruffini's corpuscle.
天哪 你已经惊慌失措了
Oh, my God, you're rattled.
将军哦
Checkmate.
我觉得他的吐槽没有自己想象的那么厉害
I don't think that was as vicious a burn as he thinks.
你赢了 没辙了
You beat me. It's over.
我已经威风扫地了
I've lost all authority.
下一个是谁
Who's next?
好吧 鲍勃
All right, Bob.
你想来硬的吗 很好
You want to play hardball? Good.
江湖传言说你喜欢爵士乐
Word on the street is, you like jazz.
何止喜欢
I don't just like jazz;
是情有独钟
I'm fond of it.
我不明白有什么区别
I don't understand the difference.
立刻告诉我档案藏哪儿了
Tell me where the file is right now,
否则我就彻底毁了你的爵士乐
or I will ruin jazz for you forever.
我倒想想瞧瞧你的本事
I'd like to see you try.
你做了个错误的决定 老伯
Wrong choice, daddy-o.
你打算怎么跟你的孩子说呢 兄弟
What are you gonna tell your kids, man?
说他们的爸爸是个骗子吗
That their daddy's a crook?
我没有孩子
I don't have any kids.
我的说词全都是基于你有孩子准备的
My whole thing was based on you having kids!
现在全都变成假设性的了
Now all of this is gonna be hypothetical.
不许用工具 迪亚兹
No tools, Diaz.
行吧 先生 我要讲五个故事
All right, mister, here are five stories
是关于我的表姐莉安和她所谓的莱姆病的
about my cousin Lee-Ann and her alleged Lyme disease.
这怎么可能套出我的话来呢
How's that gonna make me talk?
不是全世界都围着你转 鲍勃
Not everything's about you, Bob.
我只是要发泄一下
I just needed to vent.
天哪 你真是跟莉安如出一辙
God, you're such a Lee-Ann.
好了 听着 伙计
All right, listen up, buddy.
你要告诉我们东西在哪
You're gonna tell us where it is.
以及是什么东西
And also what it is.
我们对在找什么东西还有点懵
We're a little unclear what we're after.
不许用剑
No swords.
她会仰头看着你
So she's gonna look up at you,
在她假设的双眼中
with hypothetical tears
含着假设的泪水
in her hypothetical eyes,
问你为何别人假设的老爸
and ask why all the other hypothetical daddies
在职业体验日那天都来了
came in for career day.
我不行了 不能再说了
I can't. I can't.
就是说 "也许你总感到疲倦
So it's like, "Yeah, maybe you're tired all the time
是因为你得病了 莉安
"Because you're sick, Lee-Ann,
也可能只是因为你住在里诺你才抑郁"
or maybe you're depressed because you live in Reno."
怎么回事
What just happened?
有人切断了电源
Somebody cut the power.
时间到 看起来菲吉斯已经找到了你们
Time's up. Looks like Figgis found you.
好了 门挡好了
Okay, door's secure.
那是最后一根蜡烛了
That's the last of the candles.
那是多芯蜡烛吗
Is that multi-wick?
我闻到的是罗勒和柑橘的味道吗
Am I smelling basil and tangerine?
这一款叫"夏日之吻"
It's called "Summer's Kiss."
你到底是个什么人
What the hell is going on with you?
我不想触你们痛处 警探们
I hate to rub it in, detectives,
但我早就说过他们会找到我的
but I told you they'd find me.
狙击手 都趴下
Sniper! Everybody down!
- 瞄错人了 瞄错人了 - 鲍勃
- Wrong guy! Wrong guy! - Bob!
离窗户远点
Stay away from the windows!
警监 桌子
Captain, table!
天哪 怎么回事
Oh, my God. What's going on?
他们想杀我
They tried to kill me.
我们得离开这里
We have to get out of here,
我们得马上离开这里
and we have to get out of here now.
没问题 我有间避难室
It's cool. I have a panic room.
太好了 这才是我认识的罗莎
Yes! There's the Rosa I know.
"夏日之吻"见鬼去吧
"Summer's Kiss" my ass.
但装不下我们所有人
But it won't fit all of us.
看来只有把不乖的鲍勃留在外面了
Well, looks like Bob's the odd man out.
- 再见 鲍勃 - 不不不不不
- Bye, Bob. - No, no, no, no, no, no.
你们必须带上我 他们会杀了我的
You have to take me with you. They'll kill me.
听着 我会交代的
Look, I'll talk.
档案放在一个保险箱里
The file is in a safe deposit box.
钥匙在我的车尾箱内衬里
The keys are in my car in the lining of my trunk.
好吧 那行
All right, fine.
你们带鲍勃去避难室
Take Bob with you into the panic room.
罗莎和我另想办法出去
Rosa and I'll find another way out.
我相信你可以的 孩子
I'm sure you will, son.
你叫我"孩子"
You called me "son."
不许收回啦
No take-backs.
我什么时候才能开门
How will I know to open the door?
听到我敲出《性感冷艳麦迪娜》的节奏再开
When you hear me knock the "Funky Cold Medina."
我不知道《性感冷艳麦迪娜》是什么鬼
I don't know what the "Funky Cold Medina" is.
就算结合上下文也猜不出来
Even context clues have failed me.
好啦 你会知道是我的
All right, you'll know it's me.
你为什么要这么做 鲍勃
Why'd you do it, Bob?
为什么要背叛你曾经守护的一切
Why'd you betray everything you ever stood for?
我花了十四年打掉一个墨西哥贩毒团伙
I spent 14 years bringing down a Mexican cartel.
你知道他们回报我什么吗
You know what they gave me for it?
一封嘉奖信 还把我的姓写错了
A letter of commendation with my last name misspelled.
说句公道话 鲍勃
In all fairness, Bob,
谁会把"安德森"写成"安德木"呀
who spells "Anderson" with three Ns?
不管了 我想既然他们不打算尊重我
Regardless, I figured if they're not gonna give me
我还不如搞点钱
any respect, I might as well get paid.
值得吗
Was it worth it?
当然 我赚了上百万
Of course. I made millions.
我周游过世界
I traveled the world.
吃过鲸鱼
I've eaten whale.
我觉得鲸鱼肉会很肥腻
I always assumed whale would be too fatty.
我不用觉得
Well, I don't have to assume.
我很清楚就是这样
I know for a fact it is.
太恶心了
It's disgusting.
我都吐了
I threw up.
这么有节奏
That sounds funky.
肯定是杰克
Must be Jake.
怎么回事
What's going on?
哈哈 我们骗到你了 笨蛋
Ha-ha, we fooled you, you fool!
我本来想说些更酷的台词
I was gonna do something cooler,
但转念又想 "就凭感觉来吧"
but then I was just like, "Go with what you feel."
这都是谁
Who are these people?
这是我最好的朋友 查尔斯
Oh, well, this is my best friend, Charles,
这是我女朋友 艾米
and this is my girlfriend, Amy.
她其实并没怀孕
She's not really pregnant.
我们想慢慢来 但是感觉很好
We're taking things slow, but it's going really good.
- 杰克 - 对
- Jake? - Right.
他们大约一小时前到了这里
They arrived about an hour ago.
先生 我需要你给四一零号
Sir, I'm gonna need you to cut the power
罗莎・迪亚兹的房间断电
for Rosa Diaz in apartment 410.
- 四一零住的是艾米莉・戈德芬奇 - 谁
- 410 is Emily Goldfinch. - Who?
黑色卷发 特别爱笑
Curly black hair, always smiling,
就是感觉话有点多
a little chatty for my taste.
我有好多问题想问 但是没时间了
I have so many questions, but there's no time.
切断电源
Cut the power.
狙击手是查尔斯扮的
The sniper was Charles...
砰
Bang.
还有罗莎
And Rosa.
当你藏在避难室的时候
And while you were cowering in the panic room,
我去拿来了这份文件
I went and got this file
以免你说谎
to make sure you weren't lying.
那这是怎么回事
Well, what happened in here?
像是发生过一场打斗
It looks like there was a fight.
我弄的
Oh, it was me.
你们踏进房间的那一刻起 我就决定
I was done with this place the minute you all
抛弃这里了
stepped foot in it.
哎呀
Oops.
你真该接受我们的证人保护计划方案
Guess you should have taken our witness protection offer
去佛罗里达的 鲍勃
and gone to Florida, Bob.
我们现在有充足的证据
We have more than enough evidence
可以扳倒你和菲吉斯了
to take you and Figgis down.
你中计了 鲍勃
You've been played, Bob.
这都是策略
It was all a ruse.
跟杰克・佩拉尔塔共事过三年的人
You don't work with Jake Peralta for three years
怎么可能不知道"性感冷艳麦迪娜"
without knowing what the "Funky Cold Medina" Is.
那必须的
Aw, hell yeah.
"我问这哥们 '怎么这么爽'"
I asked the guy, "Why you so fly?"
"他说 '性感冷艳麦迪娜'"
He said, "Funky Cold Medina."
性感冷艳麦迪娜
Funky Cold Medina.
没排练过哦
Zero rehearsal.
我刚跟司法部通过电话
I just got off the phone with the DOJ.
他们已经逮捕了至少七十五名菲吉斯的手下
They've arrested over 75 of Figgis's men.
他的组织已经垮了
His operation is decimated.
他们抓到菲吉斯了吗
Did they find Figgis?
还没有 但是他们相信会的
Not yet, but they're confident they will.
等他们抓到他 皮门托警探就可以回来了
And when they do, Detective Pimento can come home.
等不及了
Can't wait.
我要把他的脸啃下来
I'm gonna eat his face off.
你们真是太可爱了
You guys are so cute.
我提议大家干一杯
I'd like to propose a toast.
即使是鲍勃用枪指着我的脑袋时
Even when Bob held that gun to my head,
我也毫无畏惧
I was not afraid,
因为我知道你们会追查到底
because I knew you were on the case.
我要向在座的所有人表达我由衷的敬意
I respect the hell out of each and every one of you.
- 九九万岁 - 九九万岁
- Nine-Nine. - Nine-Nine.
最喜欢听大家一起这么喊
Love it when everyone chants that.
查尔斯和我在飞机上的时候想了很多事
So Charles and I really got into it on the plane,
在吃到第五个圣代时 我突然想到
and around sundae number five, I realized
我们应该搬到一起住
we should move in together.
你和查尔斯
You and Charles?
不是 我们俩
No, you and me.
噢
Oh!
对 这样才合情合理
Yes, that makes so much more sense.
双手赞成 我们马上搬吧
Absolutely, immediately, let's do that.
我真的非常爱你
I love you so much.
我也非常爱你
Aw, I love you so much too.
我非常爱这个画面
I love this so much.
看来查尔斯一直在偷听我们说话
So I guess Charles was listening to our conversation.
是啊
Yeah.
我得接一下
Ooh, I'm gonna get this.
- 你好 - 杰克・佩拉尔塔
- Hello? - Jake Peralta?
我是吉米・菲吉斯
This is Jimmy Figgis.
噢 你好啊 哥们
Oh, uh, hey, dog.
你和雷・霍尔特搞垮了我的生意
You and Ray Holt took down my operation.
我要杀了你们
Now I'm gonna kill you both.
回见 哥们
Later, dog.
霍尔特警监
Uh, Captain Holt?
# 天空对我展舒颜 #
Blue skies smiling at me
# 碧空如洗 #
Nothing but blue skies
# 我心欢 #
Do I see
早啊 格雷格
Morning, Greg.
早 拉里
Morning, Larry.
# 青鸟翠声啼 #
Bluebirds singing a song
# 心无旁骛 #
Nothing but bluebirds
# 日悠长 #
All day long